Andrii Khorishko

Full Stack Web Developer

Summary of Qualifications

Dedicated and efficient full stack developer with 10+ years experience in application layers, presentation layers, and databases. Certified in both F/E and B/E technologies. Spearheaded successful transition from LAMP stack to MERN which cut latency by 40% and increased effectiveness of database administrators by 20%. Seeking to further improve HTML5 and CSS3 skills as the future full stack developer at Atmospheric Solutions.

Work Experience

Leader of IT Developer Team, Full Stack Developer

May 2019-June 2022

Berkeley, California, United States

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- Led a team which consisted of 5 members and published a job board website.
- Worked as a backend developer, conducted final tests of the backend and frontend of the site and optimized the speed and performance of the site.
- Made Mockup design of the website with a designer

Full Stack Developer at Diffco – US IT company

May 2014-June 2019

Sunnyvale, California, United States

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- Developed full-stack web applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data visually.
- Liaised with backend developers, front end developers, quality assurance testers, and CTO as needed.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades.
- Planned, wrote, and debugged web applications and software with complete accuracy.

Key Achievements

• Spearheaded transition from LAMP stack to MEAN stack, reducing latency by 40% and increasing database admin effectiveness by 20%.

Junior Full Stack Developer at Diffco - US IT company

December 2011–April 2014

Sunnyvale, California, United States

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- Maximized applications' efficiency, data quality, scope, operability, and flexibility.
- Used various ideas from distributed computing, large-scale design, real-time data processing, data storage, ML, and Al to solve challenging dataset problems.
- Managed, optimized, and updated PHP databases as necessary.
- Developed app integration with REST / SOAP and other APIs for Google Maps, social media logins, payment processors, and other services.

Education

University of California, Bachelor of Computer Science

Graduation: 2011

Relevant Coursework: Web Page Development, Relational Database Design & SQL, Data Engineering, Advanced Software Programming.

Uzhhorod National University

Zakarpattia, Ukraine Graduation: 2006 Studied Computer Science.

Key Skills

- Google Compute Engine
- Android and iOS App Development
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, React, Vue, Angular,
- Express.js, Python, Golang, .Net Framework
- Bootstrap, Tailwind, Mui
- My SQL, Mongo DB, Postgres SQL, Microsoft SQL Database
- AWS, Azure, Agile, Kubernetes,

Certifications

- Full-Stack Web Development with React Certification
- Front End Web Development Certificate
- Back End Web Development Certificate
- AWS Certified DevOps Engineer Professional
- Free Code Camp Full Stack Development Certification

Languages

English: FluentUkrainian: Native